edfenergy.com 2017-10-10

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | EDF Energy

## Privacy and Cookie Policy for www.edfenergy.com (the Website)

 **Last updated: June 2017**

This Privacy and Cookie Policy tells you how we will use information provided by you or collected about you when you use the Website [www.edfenergy.com](http://www.edfenergy.com/) (which includes, but is not limited to, MyAccount and MyCampus) or our mobile applications, including the EDF Energy Amazon Skill and the MyAccount application (together the “Apps”). It also explains what cookies we use on this Website.

 **Please read this Privacy and Cookie Policy carefully before you use the Website, or the Apps. It is a legally binding agreement and contains important information on your legal rights and obligations.**

 **By using this Website or the Apps you accept this Privacy and Cookie Policy and agree to abide by it.**

Expressions used but not defined in this Privacy and Cookie Policy will have the meanings set out in the Website Terms, [EDF Energy MyAccount Terms and Conditions of Use](https://my.edfenergy.com/myaccount/terms) and the [Alexa Terms and Conditions](https://www.edfenergy.com/alexa-terms-conditions) of which this Privacy and Cookie Policy forms a part.

### Changes to this Privacy and Cookie Policy

We may revise and update this Privacy and Cookie Policy at any time and will indicate at the top of this page when this Privacy and Cookie Policy was last revised. Please periodically review the Privacy and Cookie Policy, as your continued use of the Website or the Apps indicates your agreement with any changes that we make.

### Information We Collect

We collect certain personal information about you when you visit and/or register on the Website, or the Apps. The data collected will generally fall into one of four categories:

 **Information you give us:** You may give us information about you by filling in forms on the Apps or the Website, or by corresponding with us (for example, by e-mail or chat). This includes information you provide when you register to use our Apps, download or register on our Apps, subscribe to any of our services, search for a mobile application or service, make a purchase on the Website, share data via our App's social media functions, enter a competition, promotion or survey, and when you report a problem with the Website or the Apps. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, information pertaining to the device used and other registration information, and financial information, personal description and photograph.

 **Information we collect about you and your device, and usage:** Each time you visit our Website, or our Apps, we may collect the following information:

  * technical information, including the type of mobile device you use, a unique device identifier (for example, your device's IMEI number, the MAC address of the device's wireless network interface, or the mobile phone number used by the device), mobile network information, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile browser you use, time zone setting, IP addresses, browser types;
  * information stored on your device, including login information, photos, videos or other digital content, check ins;
  * details of your use of the Apps or your visits to the Website [including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise] and the resources that you access through the use of cookies. Please see the section entitled "edfenergy.com Cookies" below.

 **Location information:** We may also use GPS technology to determine your current location through your use of our Apps or using your mobile to access the Website on your phone. If you wish to use the particular feature, you will be asked to consent to your data being used for this purpose.

 **Information we receive from other sources:** We may also partner with certain third parties to deliver advertisements and monitor activities on our Website, or Apps, and in doing so these third parties may use cookies or other methods of monitoring traffic about the Website or App visitors.

If you contact us we may keep a record of that correspondence.

### Use and Storage of Your Information

This section explains how we will use your personal information. We may use the personal information you provide to us via the Website or Apps for the purposes of:

  * hosting, administering, improving the Website and Apps, or the services we offer via the Website or Apps;
  * providing you with the information your request from us and keeping a record of the information with which you have been provided;
  * to notify you about any changes to our Website or Apps, such as improvements or service/product changes, that may affect the service of the Website or Apps;
  * asking you to participate in surveys and feedback relating to the Website or Apps and for processing and analysing the results of that survey or feedback internally;
  * exercising our rights and performing our obligations under the Website Terms; the [Alexa Terms and Conditions](https://www.edfenergy.com/alexa-terms-conditions) and/or the [EDF Energy MyAccount Terms and Conditions of Use](https://my.edfenergy.com/myaccount/terms) under your energy supply contract with us;
  * providing you with information about any services we or third parties provide that we believe may be of interest to you;
  * for other purposes clearly stated on the page or other method in which you provide your information to us; 
  * to comply with legislation and regulatory laws, or other legal requirements; 
  * to share with companies within the EDF Energy group, and with trusted third parties who are contractually obligated to keep such information confidential and to use it only to provide the services that we have asked them to perform; 
  * to verify your identity and/or location to allow access to your account and to conduct online transactions; and
  * as is necessary for you to enjoy the benefits associated with use of the Website and Apps. 

### Storage of Your Information

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions carried out by us or our chosen third-party provider of payment processing services will be encrypted. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password that enables you to access certain parts of the Website or Apps, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website or the Apps; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### Sharing of Your Information

We may share your personal information with third parties in the following ways:

  * we may use third parties to process personal information on our behalf. (For example, we may use a third party to provide website or mobile application hosting services or to facilitate the provision of information to you or to provide services on our behalf);
  * we may share your personal information with third parties who may contact you directly in relation to goods or services which may be of interest to you;
  * we will release your personal information when we are required to do so for legal or regulatory purposes or as part of legal proceedings or to assist fraud protection;
  * we may disclose your identity and contact details to a third party who is claiming that any content posted or uploaded by you is a violation of their rights or who has otherwise been harmed by you in relation to your use of the Website or the Apps. You will provide us with all relevant information relating to that claim without delay;
  * we will release your personal information to others when you have given your consent to that release;
  * we may give personal information we hold about you to third parties as part of the process of selling our business; and/or
  * in some circumstances, we may transfer your personal information to countries outside of the European Economic Area. If this occurs we will take steps to ensure that adequate measures are taken to protect your personal information.

### Email Communications

To unsubscribe from marketing emails, simply click on the ‘unsubscribe’ link in the footer of the emails or update your communication preferences by logging into or registering for MyAccount and going to the About Me section.

### Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes, to the extent that is within our control. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at 0800 056 7777.

Our Website or Apps may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### Online and Mobile preferences   
edfenergy.com Cookies

This section tells you how we use cookies and how you can manage them

 **What are cookies?**  
Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer by your web browser. We use them to identify how visitors arrive at our site and the subsequent path they take through it. This helps us to improve our service to you.

EDF Energy does not use cookies to collect or store Personally Identifiable Information (PII).

 **How to control the use of cookies**  
If you wish to restrict or block cookies set by this Website, or any other website, you can do this through your browser settings. The "Help" function within your browser should give details of how to do this. Alternatively, you can find more details on how to control or delete cookies at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

Please note that you may not be able to use many of the services on our Website or Apps or other websites without cookies.

 **How edfenergy.com uses cookies**  
Our website currently uses cookies and some of our third party suppliers use our Website to set cookies on our behalf for internet marketing and performance optimisation.

While on this Website your web browser may interact with content from different servers and therefore cookies from other sources may be set on your computer during a visit to this site.

 **Optimizely cookies**

EDF Energy uses Optimizely cookies to store information about your visit to our site, helping us understand how our site is being used. We use this information to show you different content that best fits your needs, as well as allowing us to test what type of content is most popular, thus improving the user experience. All information is anonymous. These cookies do not identify you as an individual.
